<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-14T22:08:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jiaming’s Blog</title><subtitle>A personal web-page for Jiaming</subtitle><author><name>Jiaming Xiao</name></author><entry><title type="html">Structure Engineer Assistant Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FifthPost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structure Engineer Assistant Project" /><published>2019-09-27T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-09-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FifthPost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FifthPost/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time before this updating. Last time, I was going to upload 3d model of a rhino project. But I was hjacked by decorating my new house and then moving. I will try my best to upload the 3d model as soon as possible. And recently, I spent most of time hanging out with aluminum truss pedestrain bridge since there will be mid-term report for this research. On my way home from work, I began to think about a new project based on my limited work experience as a structure engineer. During my work, I realized there were bunch of routines which cost my a lot of time and probably can be done by machine. For most of rookies in my company, they have to spent most of their time on calculating and drawing. For some experienced engineers, they have to review drawings making sure its correctness. Wrong information on drawings may lead to disasters. It means if there is a drawer there shall be a drawing reviewer. If machines act as drawing reviewers, it would save experienced engineers time so that they can do much more creative work like focusing on structure analysis. In the past decade, machine learning and computer vision technology evolves fast beyond most people’s imagination. Self-driving and image detect are most popular technologies in most IT companies. With those technologies, it is not hard to create a drawing review machine which can review drawings and then search for wrong information comparing with input information (expected information). Machine is good at comparing and searching. That is why I think this part of project is not a star in the sky but an apple on a tree that will we can eat and taste it one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, a good assistant shall do repeated and boring part of a job so that engineers are able to do creative part of a job. Thus, the assistant as I expect shall think in the way of structure engineers. For instance, the assistant can automatically calcualte structures based on different structure regulations based on input information. It’s equivalent to the process of optimization with specific boundary conditions. After calculation, the assistant shall automatically finish construction drawings with input information. With the assistant, designers can concentrate on creative part of a case like new form of structures and shapes. May be it is kind of crazy now, but I still want to have a try.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jiaming Xiao</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="structure" /><category term="engineer" /><category term="assistant" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html">It’s been a long time before this updating. Last time, I was going to upload 3d model of a rhino project. But I was hjacked by decorating my new house and then moving. I will try my best to upload the 3d model as soon as possible. And recently, I spent most of time hanging out with aluminum truss pedestrain bridge since there will be mid-term report for this research. On my way home from work, I began to think about a new project based on my limited work experience as a structure engineer. During my work, I realized there were bunch of routines which cost my a lot of time and probably can be done by machine. For most of rookies in my company, they have to spent most of their time on calculating and drawing. For some experienced engineers, they have to review drawings making sure its correctness. Wrong information on drawings may lead to disasters. It means if there is a drawer there shall be a drawing reviewer. If machines act as drawing reviewers, it would save experienced engineers time so that they can do much more creative work like focusing on structure analysis. In the past decade, machine learning and computer vision technology evolves fast beyond most people’s imagination. Self-driving and image detect are most popular technologies in most IT companies. With those technologies, it is not hard to create a drawing review machine which can review drawings and then search for wrong information comparing with input information (expected information). Machine is good at comparing and searching. That is why I think this part of project is not a star in the sky but an apple on a tree that will we can eat and taste it one day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Parametric Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ForthPost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Parametric Design" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ForthPost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ForthPost/">&lt;p&gt;In the past days, I am gradually familiar with parametric design based on a gogerous software - rhino and a gogerous plug-in grasshopper. The plug-in was actually designed for interface programming and I mainly deploy the script entrance of this plug-in which is based on Python, one of my favorite programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that with those kind of tools, parametrical design can be done. Those features of rhino and grasshopper actually sounds like features of revit and dynamo. But there is difference between those softwares and plug-ins. Rhino is basically designed for architectures to find accurate 3D geometries and grasshopper makes this feature more powerful. However, the revit focuses on data of buildings and the dynamo at some level makes it more powerful. Those softwares have their own outstanding features. One for graphic computation and the other for data storing and management. I am a structre engineer in a big structure design company. As I know, most peopole in my company misunderstand about the concept of BIM and revit. They are trying to regard revit as a outstanding 3d modeling tool. Actually the power of revit is more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, I will show my first parametric design project based on rhino. May be it is kind of naive, but it has the spirit of parametric design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, the result is coming up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/2019-09-30/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Made by Jiaming Xiao &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes the steps before getting the final result&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create upper archs of the pedestrain bridge based on nodes in grasshopper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/2019-09-30/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Made by Jiaming Xiao &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I tried my best to deploy built in nodes of grasshopper since it could be easily understand by most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create lower archs of the pedestrain bridge based on nodes in grasshopper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/2019-09-30/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Made by Jiaming Xiao &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create horizontal connection along archs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/2019-09-30/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Made by Jiaming Xiao &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 4:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create surface for horizontal connection archs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/2019-09-30/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Made by Jiaming Xiao &lt;/figcaption&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Jiaming Xiao</name></author><category term="projects" /><category term="Parametric" /><category term="Rhino" /><category term="Grasshopper" /><summary type="html">In the past days, I am gradually familiar with parametric design based on a gogerous software - rhino and a gogerous plug-in grasshopper. The plug-in was actually designed for interface programming and I mainly deploy the script entrance of this plug-in which is based on Python, one of my favorite programming language.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">aluminum pedestrain bridge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ThirdPost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="aluminum pedestrain bridge" /><published>2019-04-27T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ThirdPost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ThirdPost/">&lt;p&gt;Last year, I was told to join a group focusing on aluminum pedestrain bridge. Out team will keep an eye on aluminum pedestrain bridge after work. From that day, I began to search information of aluminum pedestrain bridge through internet. Aluminum attract people’s attention because it is steel’s brother. In the early day, people optimistically regarded aluminum as replacement of steel. But aluminum disappointed those guys since its elastic module is much smaller than steel eventhough its strength is almost equal to steel. Smaller elastic module means smaller stiffness. From the persepctive of a structure engineer, truss is the best structure type for aluminum as it can largely increase stiffness of aluminum. And at beginning of this month, a colleage a gudy who focuses on structures’ appearance optimization and I was assigned to design an aluminum pedestrain bridge in Shenzhen. The purpose of this bridge is connecting two commercial center on each side of an urban highway. Challenge of this project is the bridge’s appearnce. The customers agree on advantage of aluminum pedestrain bridge. However, they can’t bear the truss structure. They need more beautiful appearance which can be harmoney with the surroundings. Besides, the width of pedestrain bridge is supposed to be so large that it will natrually connects building platforms at both ends of the bridge. For other materials like steel, the width is not definitely not a big deal. But for aluminum, large width means large stiffness of sections. After viewing references, I realized that finished aluminum pedestrain bridges are less narrow. It means we have almost no reference when solving this problem. The only way to solve this problem is create a new way.  In the past weeks, I thought through it day and night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I deployed truss arch to help improving stiffness of each span while …&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jiaming Xiao</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="pedestrain" /><category term="bridge" /><summary type="html">Last year, I was told to join a group focusing on aluminum pedestrain bridge. Out team will keep an eye on aluminum pedestrain bridge after work. From that day, I began to search information of aluminum pedestrain bridge through internet. Aluminum attract people’s attention because it is steel’s brother. In the early day, people optimistically regarded aluminum as replacement of steel. But aluminum disappointed those guys since its elastic module is much smaller than steel eventhough its strength is almost equal to steel. Smaller elastic module means smaller stiffness. From the persepctive of a structure engineer, truss is the best structure type for aluminum as it can largely increase stiffness of aluminum. And at beginning of this month, a colleage a gudy who focuses on structures’ appearance optimization and I was assigned to design an aluminum pedestrain bridge in Shenzhen. The purpose of this bridge is connecting two commercial center on each side of an urban highway. Challenge of this project is the bridge’s appearnce. The customers agree on advantage of aluminum pedestrain bridge. However, they can’t bear the truss structure. They need more beautiful appearance which can be harmoney with the surroundings. Besides, the width of pedestrain bridge is supposed to be so large that it will natrually connects building platforms at both ends of the bridge. For other materials like steel, the width is not definitely not a big deal. But for aluminum, large width means large stiffness of sections. After viewing references, I realized that finished aluminum pedestrain bridges are less narrow. It means we have almost no reference when solving this problem. The only way to solve this problem is create a new way. In the past weeks, I thought through it day and night.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hangout with Rhino</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/SecondPost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hangout with Rhino" /><published>2019-04-27T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SecondPost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/SecondPost/">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was hanging out with Rhino and Grasshopper. It is pretty interesting when trying to create fascinating shape by coding. Grasshopper and Dynamo which are the similar plugin for 3D modeling softwares.
It is not just plugins but tendency of programming in architecture design. In the old days, creating 3D modeling cost much time of engineers and designers. And it is inevitable to revise 3D models which means disaster of engineers and designers who created the 3D model. And most of their work will be meaningless and time-consuming. Graashopper and Dynamo introduced parametric modeling. It looks like the OOP in computer science. The 3D model is assembled by pieces of nodes. The models are more adpative. It frees both engineers and designers’ hands and minds so that they can pay more attention on design not modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, I hang out with rhino after work. I suppose to deploy parameter design concept to make the bridge
I design alive. Later, I will upload the codes I wrote while creating a dynamic 3D model for the pedestrain bridge I designed. 3D modeling is absolutely not a big deal today but a dynamic one under control of parameters
is interesting which means designers can change the object they design by adjusting parameters without any extra-operation like what they did in the past. And finally I suppose to import this 3d model into lumion recently introduced by my colleages is an easy to use software. It is pretty simple like playing a city simulaton game. We will see what I get in the end. Hope to share my work soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jiaming Xiao</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Rhino" /><category term="Grasshopper" /><summary type="html">Recently, I was hanging out with Rhino and Grasshopper. It is pretty interesting when trying to create fascinating shape by coding. Grasshopper and Dynamo which are the similar plugin for 3D modeling softwares. It is not just plugins but tendency of programming in architecture design. In the old days, creating 3D modeling cost much time of engineers and designers. And it is inevitable to revise 3D models which means disaster of engineers and designers who created the 3D model. And most of their work will be meaningless and time-consuming. Graashopper and Dynamo introduced parametric modeling. It looks like the OOP in computer science. The 3D model is assembled by pieces of nodes. The models are more adpative. It frees both engineers and designers’ hands and minds so that they can pay more attention on design not modeling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ideas For Structure Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/HelloWorld/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ideas For Structure Design" /><published>2019-03-30T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/HelloWorld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/HelloWorld/">&lt;p&gt;Three days ago, I found a book named Algorithimc Architecture when viewing a post through my cellphone. The title attracted me at that moment since it is coincident with my expectation about the future of architecture and structural design. That is also the reason why I finally made up my mind to be a structure
engineer after graduating from CMU. Actually, most of my classmates prefer to be an IT guy working in Silicon Valley after graduation. I still remember the day I started working in the office of the structure design company. It looks like I travelled from modern society to an ancient one by a time machine. For most desktops, the operating systems are windows 7 and the most popular tools are Autodesk CAD 2010 and the microsoft excel.
But the truth is I did not. Unlike technical companies and IT companies, architecture and structure techniques fell back in the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I found things are totally different when diving into the design work. Slow development sometime means more opportunities to change. Design is a sort of logic expression. Like human thought, there are two independent parts – ration and emotion. It is pretty hard to teach computer think emotionally though I have found engineers in google was trying to teach computers understand emotional thoughts. But it looks like not that hard to teach computers understand rational thought. Structure design is the rational part of design. There is always an explanation and logic drives people design the structures around us. Theoretically, it is approachable to teach computers understand the logic of structure design. But, paractially, we need to be patient about establishing connection between digit and structures. The cost of structure digitize is much larger beyond estimate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jiaming Xiao</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Algo" /><category term="in" /><category term="Architecture" /><summary type="html">Three days ago, I found a book named Algorithimc Architecture when viewing a post through my cellphone. The title attracted me at that moment since it is coincident with my expectation about the future of architecture and structural design. That is also the reason why I finally made up my mind to be a structure engineer after graduating from CMU. Actually, most of my classmates prefer to be an IT guy working in Silicon Valley after graduation. I still remember the day I started working in the office of the structure design company. It looks like I travelled from modern society to an ancient one by a time machine. For most desktops, the operating systems are windows 7 and the most popular tools are Autodesk CAD 2010 and the microsoft excel. But the truth is I did not. Unlike technical companies and IT companies, architecture and structure techniques fell back in the past decade.</summary></entry></feed>